NETFLIX 呈献
进攻
Attack!
快 快点 冲出去
-Go! Come on! Get out there!
快上梯子
To the ladders!
冲出去
Get out!
海因里希 来 快冲啊
Heinrich, come on, move!
我们走
Let's go!
快上梯子
To the ladders!
听我的命令
On my command!
-冲啊  -汉斯
-Charge! -Hans?
快进攻 给我冲出去
Attack! Get out there!
快 冲啊
Go! Charge!
汉斯
Hans?
-汉斯  -快点 海因里希
-Hans? -Go, Heinrich!
快冲上去
Get out there!
进攻
Attack!
快点
Keep going!
快啊
快点 再快点
Faster! Go! Faster!
快找掩护
Take cover!
海因里希
Heinrich!
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
片名：西线无战事
（海因里希葛柏）
（德国北部 1917年春）
NORTHERN GERMANY SPRING 1917
（战争第三年）
THIRD YEAR OF WAR
-保罗  -保罗
-Paul! -Paul!
保罗 喂
Paul. Hey.
怎么样
Well?
不行
那怎么办
-So, what now?
不知道
-Don't know.
-他知道我们都会去吗  -当然了
-Does he know we're all going? -Of course.
你要待在家里吗
You're staying home?
我的天 你是听妈妈话的小宝宝呀
My God, staying tied to your mummy's apron-strings?
来 我帮你签
Here, I'll sign it for you.
要他父母签才行
-His parents have to do that.
可他们没签啊 快给我
-But they didn't. Give it here.
不行的 会被发现的
-It won't work. They'll find out.
怎么可能
-How?
怎么会发现
How?
他们和他爸是笔友吗
Are they pen pals with his father?
把你的笔给我
-Give me your pen.
我没有
-I don't have one.
路德维希
Ludwig.
你会有麻烦的 他会暴打你一顿
You'll be in trouble. You'll get a thrashing.
你有更好的主意吗
Got a better idea?
总不能我一个人留下啊
I won't be the only one left behind.
太好了
Yeah!
恭喜你 博伊默尔列兵 你要上前线了
Congratulations, Private B?umer. You're going to the front.
我死定了
I'm a dead man.
你们即将步入人生的新阶段
You're standing here on the threshold of existence.
记住这一刻
Remember this moment.
这是个很重要的时刻
It's an important moment.
将来别人对你们的评价会取决于
In years to come, you will be judged on what
你们今日的勇气和作为
you dared to become today.
钢铁般的德意志青年们
The Iron Youth of Germany.
我的朋友们
My friends,
我们很幸运得以生在这个伟大的时代
you are fortunate to be living in great times.
你们的行动将化作生命之源
Your deeds will be?the water
滋养强壮而高贵的根茎
that will nourish a strong and noble root.
站好认真听 莱尼曼
Stand still and listen, Leinemann!
皇帝陛下需要的是士兵 不是孩子
The Kaiser needs soldiers, not children.
我相信我很快能见到
I am sure that I will see
你们中的大部分人归来
most of you here at home?again soon,
你们将带着荣耀归剑入鞘
your sword returned to its scabbard with honour.
你们骄傲高挺的胸前会佩戴着铁十字
With an Iron Cross pinned to your proud chest.
但是不要搞错了
But don't be fooled.
在最黑暗的时刻
During the darkest hours out
在你们等待进攻之时
there as you await an attack,
你们可能会心生疑虑
you may start to harbour doubts.
但这不是薄志弱行的时候
But this is no time for weakness of mind!
任何犹豫和迟疑都是对祖国的背叛
Any wavering, any hesitation is a betrayal of the Fatherland!
现代战争就像一盘棋局
Modern warfare is like a game of chess.
关键从来不在个人
It's never about the individual.
最重要的一直都是整体
It's always about the whole.
你们将证明自己配得上这身制服
You will prove yourselves worthy of your uniforms
突破敌人在法兰德斯的战线
and break through the enemy front in Flanders.
在那之后
And then,
就再过几个星期
in just a few weeks,
你们就会挺进巴黎了
you will finally march on Paris!
好
-Yes! -Yes!
我们的未来
Our future,
德国的未来
the future of Germany,
掌握在最伟大的一代人手中
lies in the hands of its greatest generation.
我的朋友们
My friends,
那就是你们
that's you!
对
Yes!
那么 去战斗吧
So, off to battle!
为了皇帝 上帝和祖国
For Kaiser, God and Fatherland!
好
Yes!
-太棒了  -好
-Bravo! -Yes!
下一个
Next.
保罗博伊默尔 维森格伦德53号
B?umer, Paul. 53?Wiesengrund.
1899年11月18日生
Born 18th November '99.
对吗
-Correct?
对 长官
-Yes, sir.
保罗
Paul?
给
Here.
你父亲会为你感到骄傲
Your father can be proud of you.
对
-Yes. -Next.
一切还好吗
Everything all right?
对 我就是等不及了
-Yes, I just want to get going at last.
下一个
-Next.
你走吧
Off you go.
下一个
Next.
不好意思
Excuse me.
这是别人的
This belongs to someone.
下一个
Next.
啊 可能这家伙穿起来太小了
Yes. It was probably too small for the fellow.
这是常有的事
Happens all the time.
来 祝一切顺利
Here. Take care.
谢谢
Thank you.
（海因里希葛柏）
天啊 就像量身定做的似的
Blimey, as if they were tailor-made!
喂 路德维希 这下你姑娘随便找了
Well, Ludwig, are you going to get all the girls now?
对
Yeah.
只要你不开枪打我们就行
As long as you don't shoot us.
姑娘 我爱你 我真的爱你
Girl, I do love you
但我还不能够娶你
But I can't marry you just yet
再等一年吧 就会…
Wait another year Then it will…
她不会等的 弗朗茨
She won't wait, Franz.
她不会等的
She won't wait.
你这个少女杀手
You ladykiller, you.
喝下茶一杯 还有糖和咖啡
Drink a cup of tea, sugar and coffee
再来红酒一杯
And a glass of wine
姑娘 我爱你 我真的爱你
Girl, I do love you
但我还不能够娶你
But I can't marry you just yet
再等一年吧 就会成真了
Wait another year Then it will come true
Wait another year Then it will come true…
（法国北部 拉马尔迈松 距西线25公里）
LA MALMAISON, NORTHERN FRANCE 25 KM TO THE WESTERN FRONT
这位士兵 你叫什么名字
What's your name, soldier?
克罗普 阿尔伯特克罗普 中尉
Kropp. Albert Kropp, sir.
你喜欢肮脏的姑娘吗 克罗普
Do you like dirty?girls, Kropp?
你喜不喜欢肮脏的姑娘
Do you like dirty girls?
不喜欢 中尉
No, sir.
那你怎么捧着肮脏的枪睡
Why did you sleep with one then?
凌晨3点去站岗放哨
Report for guard duty at 3 a.m.
各位 你们的战斗地点如同粪坑
Gentlemen, you'll be fighting in an absolute shithole.
你们的G98步枪最好干干净净的
And you'd better do it with a clean G98.
你们要细心呵护它
You'll pamper it.
好好爱它
You'll love it.
它要像他妈的圣母的大腿一样干净
And damn it, you'll keep it as spotless as the Holy Virgin's thighs.
明白了吗
-Do we understand each other?
遵命
-Yes, sir!
欢迎加入第78步兵预备团
Welcome to the 78th Infantry Reserve Regiment.
我们现在在西线
We're on the Western Front now.
欢迎来到巴黎
Welcome to Paris!
太好了
Yes!
妈的 怎么回事
Damn it, what happened?
我有命令要在傍晚6点前把连队送到
I have to deliver the company to the front by 6 p.m.
可以 但您得步行
You can, but on foot.
我们需要这辆卡车 中尉
We need the trucks, Lieutenant.
恕我直言 我的命令…
-With all due respect, my orders…
我他妈去你的命令
-You can stick your orders up your arse!
我有40个人在泥里奄奄一息
I've got 40 men here dying in the mud.
马上给我下车
Get out right now!
所有人都下车
Everyone out!
快点 赶紧的
Come on. Make it snappy.
你们听到军医说的了
You heard the staff surgeon.
快点 士兵们 别在这儿睡着了
Faster, soldiers! Don't fall asleep here!
快点
Come on!
弗朗茨穆勒 是吗
-Franz Müller, right?
对
-Yes.
总指挥官指望你能至少活六个礼拜
The commander-in-chief expects you to survive at least six weeks.
你想六周后还活着吗
-Do you want to be alive in six weeks?
想 中尉
-Yes, sir.
那就快走 别给我拖拖拉拉的
Then stop dragging your feet and get a move on!
听见没有
-Did you hear me?
是
-Yes.
快点
Hurry up!
这不是休闲茶会
We're not at a tea dance!
毒气
Gas!
-毒气  -毒气
-Gas! -Gas!
毒气
Gas!
快戴上防毒面具
Gas masks on!
各位
That, gentlemen,
刚才那个是个大炮弹
was a fat pig.
如果法国人再瞄准一点的话
If the French could aim better,
他们就可以拿勺子把我们从路边挖走
they'd be scraping us off the road now with a spoon
把我们埋进铁饭盒里了
and burying us in a mess tin.
但有一件事是毋庸置疑的
But one thing is as sure as eggs is eggs.
大炮弹是没有毒气的
Fat pigs don't carry gas.
向前看
Eyes front!
你是听不见吗
-Have you got cloth ears?
不是 中尉
-No, sir.
我只是忙着戴上防毒面具
I was just trying to put on my mask.
你 保罗博伊默尔 基本上活不过天亮
You, Paul B?umer, will almost certainly be dead by dawn.
你他妈的去吃点东西吧
You should eat something, damn it.
听我口令 摘下防毒面具
Attention! Gas masks off!
摘下防毒面具
Gas masks off!
你别摘
Not you.
你戴到今晚值班放哨为止
You keep yours on until guard duty tonight.
和那个笨蛋一起
With that bonehead there.
列队
Line up!
行进
March!
大家跟紧点 快走
Stick together and get moving!
抓紧时间 快点
Come on, hurry up!
保罗
Paul! Paul,
来 把你的背包给我
come on. Give me your backpack.
下次你可以帮我背
You can carry mine next time.
恭喜你们 士兵们
Congratulations, soldiers.
这是你们的新家
This is your new?home.
摘掉头盔
Helmets off!
看来我不在时这里很热闹 斯坦伯格
I see the men have been enjoying my absence, Steinberger.
我们整晚都被炮火轰炸
There was gunfire all night.
大家都要崩溃了
Their nerves are shot.
干燥的靴子会是一剂良药
Dry boots are a good remedy for that.
你想让我们都淹死吗
Do you want us all to?drown?
大家都出把力 把战壕里的水舀出去
Everyone pitches in! Bail out the trench.
你还在等什么 博伊默尔
What are you waiting for, B?umer?
还杵在那儿干什么
Why are you still standing around?
不用站岗的士兵快点舀水
给狗扔一块肉
Throw a dog a bone,
肯定会被叼走
it will always snap it up.
给人一点权力的话
Give a man power…
他会变得野蛮
Man is a beast.
喝吧
Drink.
凯特因斯基 过来 帮忙舀水
Katczinsky, come over here. Lend a hand.
我们今晚会遭到猛攻
We'll get hit hard tonight.
对不起
Sorry.
别说了
Forget about it.
这跟我想象中的不一样
This isn't how I imagined it.
闭嘴 路德维希
Shut up, Ludwig.
我的手 我的手没知觉了
My hands. I can't feel my hands any more.
把手伸进内裤里
Stick them down your trousers.
我就是这样做的
That's what I always do.
你觉得这样会有利于射击吗
You think that will make it shoot better?
你听到了吗
-Did you hear that?
什么
-What?
那个声音 你听
That sound. Listen.
什么都没有
There's nothing there.
我们的第一个法国人
Our first Frenchmen.
冷静点 小保罗
Calm down, Paulie.
我也听到了
I hear it now too.
是谁
Who's there?
嘿
Hey.
现身吧
Show yourself!
不好
No!
我中枪了
I got hit!
不 保罗 不要啊
-No, Paul. No.
怎么回事
-What's going on there?
不好了
Oh, no.
怎么回事
What is it?
那边的人朝我开枪
They shot at me from over there.
他们看到你的枪口闪光了
They saw your muzzle flash.
低调一点
Keep your heads down.
不想接住下一颗子弹 就往左挪10米
Unless you want to catch the next bullet with your teeth, move ten metres.
开枪 移动 再开枪 再移动 懂了吗
Shoot, then move. Shoot, then move. Understood?
懂了
Yes.
来
Come on.
快找掩护
Take cover!
进来
In here!
博伊默尔 克罗普 你俩快进来 快
B?umer, Kropp! You two, in here. Quick!
快进地堡
In the bunker!
快进去
Get in!
“吃东西小心点”
"Watch what you eat."
我母亲是这么叮嘱我的
That's what my mother said.
我们不离不弃 对吧
-We'll stick together, Paul.
-对  -不离不弃
-Yeah. -We'll stick together.
对
-Yeah.
我做不到 保罗
I can't do this, Paul.
我做不到 我想回家
I can't do this. I want to go home.
-嘘 -我想回家
I want to go home.
这是徐进弹幕
Creeping barrage.
什么
What?
每隔几分钟 炮火就会往前移
Every few minutes, the artillery barrage?moves forward,
而紧随其后的
and directly behind it,
就是前进的步兵
the infantry advances.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
他们来了
They're coming.
你去哪里
-Where are you going?
我马上回来
-I'll be right back.
弹幕就快结束了
The barrage is nearly over.
-不 让我走 -冷静
-No. Let me go. -Calm down.
-放我出去 我想离开这里 -冷静
-Let me out. I want to get out of here. -Calm down!
冷静
Calm down.
不要
No!
出去
Get out!
快出去
快走 出去
Move! Get out!
出去
Get out of here!
大家都出去
Everyone, get out!
保罗 那是保罗
Paul. That's Paul.
阿尔伯特
Albert!
阿尔伯特 我们找到保罗了
Albert, we've found Paul!
我们得把那根木梁移开
We have to move that beam.
保罗
Paul.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
还好吗 保罗
Are you okay, Paul?
来 保罗 起来
Come on. Paul, come on.
我来扶你
I'll help you.
来 起来 坐起来
Come on. Up you come. Sit down.
-你受伤了吗  -继续
-Are you injured? -Keep going.
保罗 你有没有受伤
Paul, are you injured?
-能听到吗  -阿尔伯特克罗普 快来帮忙
-Can you hear me? -Albert Kropp, we need help!
-回头见 保罗 -回头见 保罗
-See you later, Paul. -See you later, Paul.
凯特因斯基 赶紧的
Katczinsky, get on with it!
你呢 有没有受伤
And you? Are you injured?
没有
No.
那就开始收集吧
Then start collecting.
天啊
Oh, man!
努力才有收获
Hard work pays off.
快点 都给我抓紧了
Come on! Keep moving now!
这样下去 后天都完不成
We haven't got all day.
姓阿布雷希特 名卡尔
Albrecht, Karl.?Diepholz.
（18个月后）
18 MONTHS LATER
来自迪普霍尔茨
出生日期1898年9月14日
14th September 1898.
姓布鲁门塔尔
Blumenthal,
名萨缪尔
Samuel.
来自德累斯顿
Dresden,
出生日期1900年11月6日
6th November 1900.
昨天是他的生日
It was his birthday yesterday.
姓冯加尔维茨 名古斯塔夫
Von Gallwitz, Gustav.
奥斯纳布吕克
Osnabrück,
1899年6月20日
20th June '99.
戈茨吕特威茨…
G?tz Lüttwitz…
够了
That's enough.
（陆军最高司令部 1918年11月7日）
GERMAN HIGH COMMAND 7 NOVEMBER 1918
埃尔兹伯格先生
Mr. Erzberger.
愿上帝与我们同在
May God be with us.
光是过去几周 又有四万多人伤亡
Again more than 40,000 dead in the last weeks alone.
这应该能说服总参谋部
That should convince the general staff.
我想他们知道一切已经结束了
I think the gentlemen know it's over.
我们都知道
We all know.
元帅来了
The Field Marshal.
（法国香槟 占领区）
CHAMPAGNE, FRANCE OCCUPIED TERRITORY
谢谢
-Thanks.
不客气
-You're welcome.
按这个进度 保罗
If we keep up this pace, Paul,
我们要等180年才能征服法国
we'll have conquered France in 180 years.
我算过了
I worked it out.
你别被抓住了 凯特
Don't get caught, Kat.
绝对不会
Never.
你听
Listen.
你觉得呢 保罗 值得拼命吗
What do you think, Paul? Is it worth dying for?
饿的时候什么都值得
It is when?you're hungry.
凯特
Kat?
快跑
Run!
喂 下流的德国佬
Hey! Dirty Kraut!
快跑
Run!
你们两个真是大英雄
Men, you're heroes.
把门关上 免得其他人闻到了
Shut the door, or the others will smell it.
暗号
-Password.
我不知道 我全忘了
-I don't know. I've forgotten everything.
用你的普鲁士脑子想一下
-Use your Prussian brain.
-这里 眼睛宽 手指长 -没错
-Here. Eyes wide, long fingers.
嘴巴张开 鹅进肚肠
-Exactly. -Mouth open, goose in.
鹅鹅鹅 弗朗茨分鹅
A piece of goose from the goose. From Franz to Franz.
我要翅膀
I'll have a wing.
我一定要分享吗 剩下的给我了
Do I have to share? I'll have the rest.
大口吃吧
Well, in with it!
快来吧 你这大嘴巴鹅
Come here, you blind hen. Wide-mouthed frog.
在炮火中安息吧
-May we rest in peace under the barrage.
哦 天啊
-Oh, God.
Oh, God.
兄弟们 这一顿 我会终生难忘
Hey, boys, I'll never forget this.
好吃吗
Does it taste good?
好吃
Yes.
-你觉得呢  -很好吃
-And you? -Yes, good.
还行吧 保罗
Good, Paul?
很好 凯特
Good, Kat.
人生苦短
Life is short.
埃米尔去哪儿了
Where's Emil when you need him?
埃米尔 把咖啡和鱼子酱拿进来
Emil, bring over the coffee and caviar!
对 再放点泡脚水 我要泡脚
Yes, and run a foot bath. I need a foot bath.
凯特
Kat?
怎么了
What is it?
狐狸偷了鹅 把它还给我
You stole the goose Give it back
把它还给我
Give it back
-否则猎人会用… -养鹅人
-Or the hunter will get you… -The farmer!
养鹅人 对
The farmer! Yes!
否则养鹅人会用步枪收拾你
Or the farmer will get you With his rifle…
贾登静静地坐着说：
Tjaden sits very quietly and says,
“十字架 一天到晚就知道说十字架
"All I ever hear about is crosses."
我父亲是拿撒勒的骑士”
"My father was Captain of Nazareth."
“拿撒勒的骑士 ” 老师问道
"Captain of Nazareth?" asks the teacher.
“我从来没听说过 贾登 你回家问清楚 好吗 ”
"Never heard of it. Tjaden, go home and ask again, okay?"
第二天 贾登冲进教室说：
The next morning, Tjaden rushes into the classroom and says,
“真是抱歉
"I'm so sorry,
我父亲不是拿撒勒的骑士
my father wasn't Captain of Nazareth."
我父亲是喜欢拿沙拉里的起司”
"My father had the clap in a lazaret."
快看
Look!
喂 你们好
Hey! Hello!
过来呀
Come here!
我们有长棍面包
Fresh baguette!
给你们的
For you!
德国肝香肠 亲爱的
Leberwurst, love!
满满的爱哦
Lots of love!
喂 弗朗茨 你要去哪里
Hey, Franz, where are you going?
带我一起去
-Take me with you!
好 来啊
-Come on then!
你们看
Look!
他这是在自取其辱
Now he's making a fool of himself.
我的天啊
Ooh la la!
你好美丽啊 亲爱的
You're very beautiful, my love.
弗朗茨
Franz!
瘦瘦的黑头发的那个是我的
The skinny dark-haired one is mine!
他要去哪里
Where's he going now?
弗朗茨
Franz?
再见
Goodbye!
再见 我的朋友们
Goodbye, my friends!
妈的
Damn.
如果一切都结束了
If it was all over now,
你知道我会怎么做吗
you know what I'd do?
还没有和平 还没结束呢
There's no peace. It's not over.
我知道 假设的话
But if it was.
妈的 那就又可以泡妞了
-Bloody hell, there'd be girls again.
那倒也是
-Yes, indeed.
我一连八天都不会穿裤子
I wouldn't wear any trousers for a week.
你在这里说这种话 我该打你屁股了
I should smack your arses for bringing that up.
你呢 保罗
What about you, Paul?
不知道 我想不出来
-No idea. Can't think of anything.
我会和普鲁士人待在一起
-I'd stay with the Prussians.
你疯了 贾登
You're crazy, Tjaden.
你挖过泥炭吗
Have you ever dug?peat?
改天试试看
Try it one day.
总不能比在香槟挖战壕更糟
Can't be worse than digging trenches.
比在香槟挖战壕耗时多了
Takes longer than digging trenches.
而且还不能偷懒
And you can't slack off either.
在和平时期的军队里 你无忧无虑
In the army during peacetime, you have no worries.
每天早上 吃的都给你准备好
Food's there every?morning,
要不然就大闹一场
or you raise a stink.
你还有舒服的床
Then you've got your nice bed,
每周有新换的床单
fresh sheets every week.
然后
And then…
然后你可以当士官
Then you make NCO.
想象一下
Imagine that.
我当了一个乡警
I'll be a police ranger.
这里一杯白兰地 那里一杯啤酒
A cognac here, a pint there.
每个人都想和乡警搞好关系 每个人
Everyone wants to be friends with a ranger. Everyone.
但有一个问题 贾登
There's just one catch, Tjaden.
什么问题
What's that?
你永远都当不上士官
You'll never make NCO.
你净问些莫名其妙的问题
You always ask such nonsense questions.
根本无济于事
It won't change anything.
-凯特  -这里
-Kat! Kat! -Here!
-Kat! -Here!
“我的小胖仔
"My dumpling."
你让我寄一包吃的过来
"You asked for a food parcel."
四份香肠和猪油在路上了
"Four helpings of wurst and lard are on their way…
几个蛋糕
a few cakes,
还有酸菜和小牛肉肠
sauerkraut and bockwurst,
还有一盒
and…
兴…
Hing…
-兴芳止痛剂和方糖 -兴芳
Hingfong essence with sugar cubes,
一些鸡蛋和一罐李子酱
some eggs and a jar of plum jam."
别一次吃完 我不想马上又寄一批
"Make it last because I don't want to have to send more too soon."
最好不要跟你的同志们分享
"Better not share it with your comrades."
我亲爱的小胖仔
"My dear dumpling,
我想问你一件事
I have another question for you."
你目前存了多少钱
"How much money have you saved so far?"
你能寄些回家吗
"Can you maybe send some home?"
他们说战争很快就要结束了
"They say that the war will be?over soon,
有余钱的话自然是好的
so it would be good to have some left over."
现在你会想：
"Now you'll think,
‘这个老女人 脸皮真厚’
listen to the old lady, how cheeky!"
但我不介意
"But no offence."
你知道我的 我永远都嫌不够
"You know me, I can't get enough."
我总是要更多 不知足是我的座右铭
"Give me an inch and I'll take a mile."
所以你不要在终点前倒下
"So don't keel over on the home stretch."
卡尔莱默已经在东线住院了
"Karl Lemmer is already in a field hospital in the East."
说是肚子出了问题
"Something to do with his stomach.
他去前线还没满三周呢
He was hardly out there three weeks."
你有风湿 不能因为生病回家吗
"Can't you get off too, with your rheumatism?"
难道你做得还不够多吗 ”
"You've done your bit."
要是她现在能看到你就好了
If only she could see you now,
坐在这里抽着雪茄
sitting here with your cigar!
“这个周日我会去…
"On Sunday, I'm visiting…"
这个周日我会去我们小儿子的墓地
"On Sunday, I'm visiting our little boy's grave."
我会念书给他听 他一直都很喜欢
"I'm going to read to him. He always liked that so much."
明年我们一起去 庆祝他的十岁生日
"Next year, we'll go together and celebrate his tenth birthday."
好的 就说这些吧
"Well, that's all I had to say."
我亲吻你 我的丈夫
"Kisses from your wife."
再见”
"Goodbye."
我之前都不知道
I didn't know.
哦 保罗
Oh, Paul.
接下来会怎么样
What's going to happen?
总有一天会回家
Going home someday…
回到以前的生活
Going back to our old lives.
而他们只想知道 我们有没有近距离作战
And all they'll want to know is if we fought in close combat.
我们会像过往风景中的过客一样
We'll walk around like travellers in a landscape from the past.
我问自己
I ask myself…
我是不是宁愿
if I wouldn't just rather sit around
在这里和你
a campfire with you
还有贾登 克罗普
and Tjaden and Kropp
还有穆勒坐在营火旁
and Müller…
吃炸土豆
and eat fried potatoes.
连皮吃
With the skin on.
是啊 Yeah…
我无聊了
I'm bored.
我们还要多久才能出发
How long until we get going again?
到底还要多久
How long until we get going?again?
弗朗茨
Franz?
什么事
Yeah?
我们明天6点就得离开
We have to leave?at six tomorrow.
去找几个小伙子
To look for some kids.
出什么事了
What happened?
他们应该早就到了
They should have arrived today.
整个连的人
An entire company.
你那边怎么样
How was it?
嗯 很好
-Nice.
是吗
-Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
来
Here.
你闻闻
Smell.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
艾洛伊丝
Eloise.
她的皮肤 白得像牛奶
Her skin was as white as milk.
还有她的胸…
And her breasts…
喂
Hey.
我也想闻
I want a turn.
阿尔伯特
Albert.
-克罗普 给我 -你闻闻
-Kropp. Let me have it. -Here.
-我的天啊 -贾登
-Oh, my! -Tjaden.
像这样的姑娘连指甲缝都从不会脏
A girl like that never has dirty fingernails.
-对 -顶多有点沙滩上的沙子
-No. -At most, a bit of sand from the beach.
贾登
Tjaden.
-快点 还给我 -她肯定一天要泡两次澡
-Come on, give it to me. -I'm sure she has a?bath?twice a day.
贾登
Tjaden.
拜托 这是我的
Please. It's mine.
贾登
-Tjaden!
不给 这是我的了
-No, it's mine now.
这可不是一般的炮火啊
That was one hell of a blast.
这是迫击炮
Trench mortar.
人都从军装里被炸飞了
It blasted him right out of his uniform.
他是我们要找的人吗
Is he one of those we're looking for?
不 他们是昨天才失踪的
No, they've only been missing since yesterday.
他挂那儿一段时间了
He's been up there a while.
那倒确实
Not funny.
现在不要心软
Don't start getting soft, men.
我们要找几个人
-How many are we looking for?
60名年轻新兵
-Sixty young recruits.
早餐吃萝卜面包
Turnip bread for breakfast.
午餐吃萝卜面包
Turnip bread for lunch.
成天都吃萝卜面包 我受够了
Turnip bread all the time. I've had enough.
你们找到了告诉我 我一步都不想走
Tell me when you've found them. I'm not taking another step.
毒气
Gas.
这里有过毒气
There was gas here.
好嘞
Yes.
你好 女士
Hello, madam.
我是克罗普
I'm Kropp.
你呢
And you?
你想…
Do you want to…
你想跟我走吗
Do you want to come with me?
没问题
Not a problem.
凯特
Kat.
Kat!
凯特
妈的
Shit.
-这些孩子们啊 -是啊
-Bloody kids. -Yeah.
他们太快摘下面具了
They took their masks off too soon.
德国很快就会没人了
Soon, Germany will be empty.
（法国 贡比涅 1918年11月8日）
将军
Sir.
布里克斯多夫 有什么最新消息
Well, Brixdorf, what's the latest?
法国人在施加压力 将军
The French are putting the pressure on.
今早我们的侦察员拦截到了
Early this morning, our scouts intercepted orders
让全师兵力到拉蒂尔集结的命令
summoning entire divisions to Latierre.
一队坦克仍被困在费尔南库尔特
A fleet of tanks is still stuck in Fernancourt.
我们得做好迎接袭击的准备
We need to prepare for an attack.
社会民主党人将是人类的末日啊
The Social Democrats will be the end of mankind, Brixdorf.
将军
Sir?
我刚刚送德国代表团去进行停火谈判
他们正坐火车去贡比涅
to negotiate a ceasefire.
这些人啊 布里克斯多夫
These people, Brixdorf,
他们要出卖我们的祖国
are selling off our fatherland.
我的命令是战争
My order is war.
只要这点不变 我必定会全力奋战
And as long as that's the case, I'll fight tooth and nail.
我们必须坚持住 等待新来的援军
We have to hold firm and wait for fresh troops.
再过几个月 新兵就要到了
New recruits are due in a few months.
法国人想将那些狗屁条件强加于我们
The French are trying to force their shitty terms on us.
我不会投降
I will not surrender.
我们现在必须出击
We have to strike now
全力出击
with all our might.
是 将军
Sir.
以我们的立场
For our part,
我坚持要求…
I have to insist…
我们坚持要求…
we have to insist…
妈的
For God's sake!
真他妈的
Shit.
中尉
Sir!
士兵们 快收拾东西
Soldiers, pack your bags,
把铺盖被罩卷好 把炊具餐具洗了
roll up your bedding and wash your mess kits.
整个团都要向前线进发
The entire regiment is being sent to the front line.
凡是两只腿可以站起来的人都要去
We're taking anyone who can stand on two legs.
快点排好队 妈的
Line up, damn it!
难道法国人会等着你们梳阴毛吗
You think the French will wait for you to comb your pubes?
我们又要走了
Here we go again.
-快点  -去哪里
-Move it! -Where to?
“去哪里 ”
Where to?
去打仗啊
Into battle.
元帅在等各位过去
Monsieur le Maréchal is expecting you.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
嫉妒吧
Jealous?
我站在你们面前
I stand before you
是希望你们能将我们的到访
in the hope that you will take our presence as an opportunity
看作暂停一切敌对活动的契机
to suspend all hostilities.
以人性之名
In the name of humanity,
我请你们同意立即停火
I ask you to agree to an immediate ceasefire
在整个谈判期间都不交战
for the duration of our?negotiations
以免我们各自的国家有不必要的损失
in order to spare our nations any unnecessary losses.
马蒂亚斯埃尔兹伯格
Matthias Erzberger,
德国代表团团长
head of the German delegation.
福煦元帅问诸位此行的目的是什么
Marshal Foch asks what brings us gentlemen to him.
我们想听听您的建议
We look forward to your suggestions
看看如何达成最终的停火
for bringing about?a permanent ceasefire at sea,
陆 海 空全线停火
on land and in the air.
我对你们没有任何建议
I don't have any suggestions for you.
他这是何意
What does he mean?
我觉得他可能不喜欢您的措辞
I think he might not like how you phrased it.
好吧
Yes.
那么 这个…
Okay, then…
元帅先生
if you please,
如果您愿意
我们想知道具体条件
we would like to know the conditions…
他想让您正式提出请求
He wants you to formally ask for it.
元帅先生
Monsieur le Maréchal,
我请求您停战
I'm asking you for an armistice.
你们有72小时接受我们的条件
You have 72 hours to accept our conditions.
没有商量的余地
They are non-negotiable.
-72小时  -战争将持续到您签字为止
-72 hours? -The war will continue until you sign.
元帅先生
Monsieur le Maréchal,
以上帝之名 别让战争再持续72小时
in the name of God, don't let 72 hours go by.
很多人已经丧命
People are dying out there.
那就签字吧
Sign then.
明白了
Understood.
让士兵们前进
Soldiers, march.
士兵们 前进
前进吧 士兵们
March, soldiers.
士兵们 前进
Soldiers, march.
走吧 快上去
Let's go. Out of here!
前进吧 士兵们
March, soldiers.
前进
March.
士兵们 前进
Soldiers, march.
士兵们 前进 快走
March, soldiers. Out of here!
冲啊
Charge!
-快点  -冲啊
-Faster! -Hooray!
进攻
Onwards, men!
上
Charge!
冲啊
Hooray!
保持队形
Keep ranks!
不要停
Keep going!
快
Go, go, go!
我们走 保罗 快
Let's go, Paul. Come on.
保罗
Paul!
快出去
Get out!
开火
Open fire!
趴下
Get down!
快找掩护
Take cover!
快出去
Get out of here! Get out!
原地不动 紧密作战
Stay where you are and close ranks!
手榴弹
Hand grenades!
他们开到上面的时候 瞄准履带
Aim for the tracks when they're above us.
走 兄弟们
Let's go, men!
快走 弗朗茨
Go! Franz!
弗朗茨
Franz!
跟我走
Follow me!
弗朗茨
Franz!
来 跟我来
Come on! Follow me!
弗朗茨
Franz!
保罗
Go! Come on! Paul!
冲啊
Charge!
保罗
Paul.
Paul!
开火
Open fire!
撤退
Retreat!
不要 别开枪
No, don't shoot! No!
不要
No! No!
不要 别开枪
Don't! Don't shoot!
阿尔伯特
Albert.
-Albert. -Come on!
快走
Come on!
别停下
Keep going!
弗朗茨在哪里
Where's Franz?
弗朗茨不见了
I've lost Franz!
凯特因斯基
Katczinsky!
拿好机枪就撤退
Secure the machine gun and retreat!
然后往东北两公里到伊吉萨克集合
We'll regroup in Eguisac, two kilometres northeast of here.
我想念我的同伴了 中士
I am missing my comrades, Sergeant!
我还想我妈呢 妈的
And I miss my mother, damn it!
拿上手榴弹和弹药 我们走
Grenades! Ammunition! Let's go!
保罗 快走
Paul, come on!
这些不是谈判条件 而是律令
This isn't a negotiation. This is a diktat.
也许我们应该回斯帕 跟总参谋部商量一下
Maybe we should return to Spa to consult with the general staff.
您觉得那会有什么用
And what good will that do?
就算我们最终输了
Even if we end up losing,
结果也不会比投降更糟
we won't be any worse off than with this surrender.
但是会多死掉几十万人
Besides a few hundred thousand more deaths.
阿尔萨斯洛林 占领莱因河
Alsace-Lorraine, occupation of the Rhine,
大炮 机车 火车
artillery, locomotives, trains.
这是彻彻底底的投降啊
This is total capitulation!
每个月有25万美国人来到欧洲
250,000 Americans are landing in Europe every month.
马恩 坎蒂尼 康布雷 全部输了
Marne, Cantigny, Cambrai, all lost.
唯一阻碍我们停火的就是虚无的自尊
The only thing separating us from a ceasefire is false pride.
是时候该处理您和将军们的烂摊子了
It's time to deal with the mess you and your generals have left us.
但如果您想离开 那么请便
But if you'd rather leave now, go ahead.
我们会留在这里
We're staying here.
现在是冬天
It's winter.
没了火车和物资 布尔什维克会击垮我们
Without trains and provisions, the Bolsheviks will overrun us.
士兵们会在回家的路上饿死
The men will starve on the way home,
而不是在战场上光荣战死
instead of dying with honour on the battlefield.
光荣战死
Honour?
我儿子战死了 但他并不感到光荣
My son was killed in this war. Where's his honour?
冯海尔道夫
Von Helldorf.
请把协约国所提要求的副本 通过电报发给总部
Get a few copies of the Allied demands and telegraph them to headquarters.
你去通知政府
Inform the government.
诸位 我们有72个小时
We have 72 hours, gentlemen,
每浪费一分钟 就又有一个士兵死去
and every minute we waste talking here, another soldier dies.
我们接受能得到的慈悲吧
Let's find mercy where we can,
但是 看在上帝的份上
but for God's sake,
我们停战求和吧
let's end this war.
撤退
Retreat!
他们撤退了 加强火力
They're retreating! Barrage!
加强火力
Barrage!
别出声
Be quiet!
闭嘴
Shut up.
Shut up!
不要
No!
同志
Comrade.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
（杰拉德杜瓦尔 排字员）
你的家
House…
你的妻子
Your wife…
我保证
I promise.
我保…
I pro…
你什么时候出生的 布里克斯多夫
When were you born, Brixdorf?
1877年6月
1877, in June.
夏天出生的孩子
A summer child.
是的
Yes.
你父亲是做什么的
What does your father do?
我家在荷尔斯泰因有一间工坊
My family owns a manufactory in Holstein.
什么样的工坊
What kind?
骑马用的马鞍 将军
Riding saddles, sir.
马鞍
Riding saddles.
马鞍永远有销路
They'll always sell.
您的未来很有保障
Your future is safe.
我很幸运
I'm very lucky.
那么
Well?
你期盼着回家吗
Looking forward to going home?
当这里不再需要我们的时候
-When we're not needed here any more?
是的
-Yes.
战后有一份工作等着我
There's a job waiting for me after the war.
我会接手家里的生意
I'll take over the business.
恭喜
Congratulations.
您呢
What about you?
我是个战士
I'm a soldier.
我父亲曾是一个团的军官
My father was an officer in this regiment.
他参加了俾斯麦领导的三场战争
He fought in three wars under Bismarck.
他三场都赢了
He won all three.
他在1871年率军挺进巴黎
In 1871, he marched on Paris.
然后英雄凯旋
He came home a hero.
我生不逢时啊 布里克斯多夫
I was born too late, Brixdorf.
半个世纪都没有战争
Half a century without war.
没有战争 那战士有何用
What is a soldier without war?
您跟您父亲亲近吗
Were you close to your father?
或许小时候还行吧
As a child, perhaps.
独自来到世上的男人
A man is born alone,
独自活着
he lives alone,
独自死去
and he dies alone.
（德国皇帝宣告退位）
THE KAISER HAS ABDICATED
进来
Come in.
冯海尔道夫 什么事
Von Helldorf, what is it?
兴登堡来函
Hindenburg.
快快打开
Open it then.
他在催我们签字
He urges us to sign.
结束了
It's over!
敲开修道院的门
Knock on the monastery door,
你只会发现小偷和无赖
and you'll find only thieves and scoundrels.
都结束了 那些肥猪终于意识到了
It's over. The fat pigs have realised.
他们终于在谈判了
They're negotiating at last.
我们马上就要回家了 战士
We're going home soon, soldier!
医务室在哪里
Where's the infirmary?
不要
-No!
快给他上氯仿麻醉
-Just chloroform the man!
博伊默尔
B?umer.
-贾登 -博伊默尔
-Tjaden. -B?umer.
怎么回事 你哪里受伤了
What happened? Where did you get hit?
膝盖上面
Above the knee.
好像是
I think.
我什么都感觉不到
I can't feel anything.
伤口离膝盖有多远
How far above the knee was I shot?
我没办法抬头看
I can't lift my head.
至少10厘米吧
Ten centimetres at least.
你要回家了 贾登
-You're going home, Tjaden. -You think so?
-是吗  -肯定的
Yes, of course.
我这样要怎么当乡警
How can I be a ranger like this?
真他妈的
For Christ's sake!
你还是可以的
You still can.
你等着瞧
You'll see.
我不会让他们截肢的
I won't let them amputate.
我绝对不要瘸着过活
I won't live as a cripple.
不需要的
You won't have to.
他们处理过比这还糟糕得多的
They've patched up much worse here.
哦 保罗
Oh, Paul.
我应该给你一样东西
I'm supposed to give you something.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
你必须得勇敢起来
You have to be brave now.
你还活着
You're alive.
你一定要心怀感激
You have to be grateful for that.
为了我们
For us.
为了那些没能活下来的人
For those who didn't make it.
别说了
Be quiet.
听着 你不可以这么说 你不可以
Listen, you can't say that. Not you.
我知道你们要吃饭 但人还没到齐
你喂不上他们了 他们不在医务室就在墓地
They're in the infirmary or mass graves.
快点舀饭 我们闻得出已经好了
-Dish it up. We can smell it's done.
那不行
-I can't.
为什么不行 你个无赖
Why not, you vagrant?
我煮了150个人的份
I've cooked for 150.
150个人的不能只给80个人吃
I can't serve 80 men food for 150!
你是脑子有屎吗
Are you thick as pig shit?
你收到了第二连队的口粮
You've received provisions for the second company.
我们就是第二连队
-We're the second company!
对
-Yes!
快点给饭吧 快点
So dish it out, full stop!
凯特
Kat!
-凯特  -保罗
-Kat! -Paul!
凯特
Kat!
保罗
Paul!
凯特 你还活着
-Paul! -Kat, you're alive!
你还活着
You're alive!
保罗
Paul!
贾登中弹了
Tjaden got hit.
他在教堂里躺着
He's in the church.
我们给他拿双份的饭
He'll get a double helping from us.
对 来吧
-Yes. -Come on.
小心
Careful.
再来一份
And one here too.
妈的 我还以为你死了呢
Bloody hell, I thought you were dead.
人迟早都要死
We'll all die at some point.
但不能在就要回家时死
But not on the home stretch.
如果你死在我前头 我会杀了你
If you die before me, I'll kill you.
贾登
Tjaden.
-凯特  -对
Kat?
凯特
Kat.
我们拿了点汤来
We brought you some soup.
有餐具吗
Did you bring some cutlery?
有 餐具也拿了
Yes, we brought some cutlery too.
吃吧
Enjoy it.
不要 住手贾登
No! Tjaden, stop! Stop it, Tjaden!
贾登 住手
Tjaden, no!
快来人啊
We need help here!
你为什么要这么做
Why did you do that?
为什么
Why?
结束了 兄弟们 都结束了
It's over, boys, it's over.
他血快流光了
He's bleeding out!
贾登
Tjaden.
怎么了
What is it?
我有样东西不见了
I've lost something.
凯特 你会说法语吗
Kat, can you speak French?
比如“请”
我母亲当初要我学法语来着
My mother wanted me to learn French.
这样啊
还有钢琴
And piano.
她不希望我上战场
She didn't want me to go to war.
她说：“那不是你该做的
"It's not for you," she always said.
你没几天就会死”
"You'll be dead in no time."
我想向他们证明我能做到
I wanted to show them I could do it.
结果我们是这种境遇
How does that help us now?
还说什么再过几周就到巴黎了
"In a few weeks, we'll be in Paris."
不断扔手榴弹的这两年
I can't discard two years of hand grenades
可不像臭袜子说脱就脱
like a pair of socks.
保罗
-Paul…
我们永远无法去除这股恶臭
-We'll never get rid of the stench.
-够了 -路德维希死了 弗朗茨死了
-Enough. -Ludwig's dead, Franz,
-阿尔伯特… -这关我们什么事
Albert… What's it to us now?
他们安息了
At least they're at peace.
我们还活着
We're alive.
这里的一切就像发烧一样
All of this is like a fever.
没人真的想要发烧 但它突然就来了
No one actually wants it, but suddenly it's here.
我们不想要 其他人也不想要
We didn't want it, the others didn't want it.
但我们来了 全世界也卷进来一半
And yet, here we are. And yet, half the world is here.
上帝就这样看着
And God watches on
看着我们彼此屠杀
as we slaughter each other.
就是这样
Well…
但我又知道什么呢
But what do I know?
我什么都不知道
I know nothing.
我是一双带着步枪的靴子
I'm a pair of boots with a rifle.
去睡吧 我们运气好
Get some sleep. We got lucky.
好
Yes.
凯特
Kat?
嗯
你儿子是怎么死的
What did your son die of?
天花
Smallpox.
我害怕接下来会发生的事
I'm afraid of what's to come.
别怕
Don't be.
亨利
Henri.
尝尝
Taste it.
这是今天做的吗
Are they fresh?
对不起 先生 应该不是
I'm sorry, sir, but I don't think so.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
皇帝已经退位了
The Kaiser has abdicated.
士兵们拒绝服从命令
Soldiers are refusing to obey?orders.
逃兵在乡下游荡
Deserters are roaming the countryside.
新政府将尽全力履行需要担当的职责
The new government will do its utmost to fulfil the duties imposed on it,
但是并没有犯错的平民百姓
but the population, through no fault of its own,
却可能面临饥荒和无政府混乱
risks descending into famine?and anarchy.
这是败者的问题 而非胜者的问题
This is a disease of the defeated, not of the victorious.
我不怕
I don't fear it.
我拒绝任何妥协
I reject any compromise.
元帅先生 拜托了
Monsieur le Maréchal, please.
请公平对待您的对手 否则和平会令其愤懑
Be fair to your enemy, otherwise he will hate this peace.
公平
Fair?
您还要谈公平
You speak of fairness?
签字吧
Sign it.
会议记录将写明
Let the minutes record
停战协议将在六小时后
that the armistice will take effect in six hours
即11月11日的上午11点生效
at the 11th hour on the 11th day of the 11th month.
很好
Very good.
战争结束了
The war is over.
您现在打算怎么做
What will you do now?
你看到了什么 布里克斯多夫
What do you see here, Brixdorf?
拉蒂尔平原 将军
The plains of Latierre, sir.
伊吉萨克
Eguisac.
我也看到了
I see them too.
还有德国士兵 像兔子一样逃跑
And German soldiers running away like rabbits.
法国人在拉蒂尔打得我们屁滚尿流
The French are farting into our posts in Latierre,
外面还有一火车的王八蛋
and out there is a train full of horse fuckers,
想要出卖祖国
selling off our homeland.
让所有新兵撤离兵营
Withdraw the recruits from all posts.
让他们到院子里报到
Have them assemble in the courtyard.
我们他妈的要收拾这个烂摊子
We're going to sort out this shitty mess!
继续严禁与敌人进行一切通讯
Any communication with the enemy remains prohibited.
第一 西线所有敌对行动于今日停止
Firstly, hostilities on the entire front will cease today,
从11月11日上午11点起生效
11th November, at 11 o'clock in the morning.
第二 全体部队禁止继续前进
Secondly, troops will not cross the lines held on this day, at this hour.
就停留在今日此刻的位置
The lines will be accurately marked…
几点了
What time is it?
你怎么不睡啊
-Why aren't you sleeping?
你听
-Listen.
好安静啊
It's so quiet here.
就像我耳聋了一样
I think I've gone deaf.
他们已经签字了 保罗
They've signed, Paul.
战争结束了
The war's over.
结束了
It's over.
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
快点 趁那个混蛋还没醒
Come on, before the bastard wakes up.
你圣诞节做什么 保罗
-What are you doing for Christmas, Paul?
不知道
-I don't know.
我要烤鹅吃
I'm roasting a goose.
配上红甘蓝和土豆
With red cabbage, potatoes.
然后我要点上所有蜡烛
Then I'll light all the candles
再亲吻我的老婆
and kiss my wife.
哎 保罗 我老婆可漂亮了
My God, Paul. My wife, she's beautiful.
-是吗  -对
-Yeah? -Yeah.
她长什么样
-What does she look like?
嗯
-Well…
长卷发 深色的
Long, dark, curly hair.
而且她又圆又结实
And she's round and strong.
圣诞节
Christmas.
好遥远啊
It's all so far away.
其实并不遥远 很快就到了
But it isn't. It's very soon.
我们想再要一个孩子
We want another child.
好几个孩子 保罗
Children, Paul.
没有孩子的圣诞节算什么 没意义
Because what's Christmas without children? It's nothing.
对吧
你知道的
You know, once…
等我们回家了
Once we're back home, then…
-嗯  -我们要干点大事
-Yeah? -We'll do something big.
我们两个一起 好吗
The two of us together, okay?
唉
Well…
怎么了
What?
我是补鞋匠 保罗
I'm a cobbler, Paul.
我是修鞋的 懂吗
I repair shoes. Yeah?
你懂得读书写字 你有高中文凭
You can read, write. You have your school diplomas.
但也没什么用啊
Didn't do me any good.
那我们做什么
What are we going to do?
给鞋子钉鞋底 我们两个
Nail soles on shoes together?
你是想羞辱我吗
Are you trying to insult me?
我连我老婆的信都看不懂
I can't even read a letter from my wife.
你要去读书 保罗
Go to college, Paul.
不然我现在就毙了你
Or I'll shoot you right here.
我的裤子要掉了
My trousers are falling down.
我的裤子松了
My trousers are loose.
你多吃一点就好了
You'll just have to eat a little.
很快我们就回家了 想吃什么随便吃
Soon we'll be home, then we can eat what we want.
随便吃
Whatever we want.
该你了
It's your turn.
如果养鹅的再发现我的话
If the farmer catches me again,
他应该会开枪打我
he'll shoot me.
小心那条臭狗
Watch out for the damn dog.
好的
Yeah.
嘘
你看
Look.
真的很不错
It's really good.
你要吗
Want some?
妈的
Shit.
站住
Stop!
凯特
Kat!
快跑
Run!
王八蛋
Bastard!
妈的
Damn.
哦 他妈的
Oh, crap.
快看
Look at this.
怎么了
What is it?
我运气太好了
-I got lucky.
打的是蛋吗
-He hit the eggs?
-用手按着 -好
-Press on it. -Okay.
-全都倒进去 -好
Come on, get?
全倒进去
it all in there. All of it.
我们可以煎了吃
We can fry them.
胡说八道 我们现在就吃
Nonsense. We'll eat them right now.
这样也行
Like this is fine too.
这味道简直了
Doesn't get better than that.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
凯特
Kat?
Kat!
怎么了
What happened?
我们走
Let's go.
谁开的枪
-Who fired the shot?
养鹅场的小屁孩
-The little shit from the farm.
养鹅户的儿子
The farmer's boy.
凯特
Kat!
真是一团糟
What a mess.
有多大
How big?
小手指那么大
Little finger.
我把子弹弄出来
I'll get the bullet out.
不 给我一根烟就好
No, just give me a cigarette.
让医护员来吧
Leave that to the?medic.
他们让我和七岁的孩子一起上课
They stuck me in a class of seven-year-olds.
我当时已经开始刮胡子了
I had already started shaving.
找一个跟“骨气”押韵的词
Find a word… that rhymes with trifle.
没有词和骨气押韵啊 没有
Nothing rhymes with trifle. Nothing.
真他妈的
For Christ's sake!
为什么要偏偏挑这个时候
Did it have to happen now, of all times?
-来吧 我们得走了 -好
-We have to keep going. -Yeah.
走吧
Keep going.
你可以吗 凯特
Okay? Kat?
武器
Rifle.
嗯
武器和骨气押韵
Rifle rhymes with trifle.
回家之后 你得给我做一双新靴子
When we get home, you're going to make me a new pair of boots.
我的脚都走出血了
I'm walking my feet bloody.
停车
Stop!
快停下
医护员
Medic!
其实你不用白费力气
You could've saved yourself the trouble.
啊
他死了
He's dead.
可是 那只是一个很小的枪伤
对 血都黑了 直接进入了肝脏
Yes, black blood. Straight into the liver.
器官中毒了
His organs are poisoned.
他是昏过去了
Unconscious.
不
他死了
He's dead.
这个我应该比你懂
I know more about these things.
不可能 我刚才还跟他说话来着
他是昏过去了
He's unconscious. He's unconscious.
你看到了吗
You see?
他很倒霉 眼看就要到终点了
He was just unlucky. So close to the end.
走吧 士兵
Come along, soldier!
将军让我们回家了
The General's sending us home!
我们要回家了
We're going home!
快走
Go on, keep going!
快一点
Step it up a notch!
立正
Attention!
战士们
Soldiers,
我们作为兄弟站在这里
we stand here as brothers
在敌人的世界里
in a world of enemies,
我们被迫看着德国社会民主党人
forced to watch as German social democrats render
让我们亲爱的人民毫无还手之力
因为他们接受了卑鄙叛国的停战协议
by accepting a perfidious armistice.
同志们
Comrades,
很快你们就会回家
you will be going home soon
见到你们的父母 妻子和孩子
to parents, wives and children.
战争结束了
The war is over.
你们多年的牺牲和磨难终有好的回报
After years of sacrifice and suffering, you can now look forward to your reward.
那就是你们在这里赢得的尊敬
The reward of admiration for everything you've achieved here.
但是 同志们
But, comrades,
你们想被当成战士和英雄受到欢迎
do you want to be welcomed as soldiers and heroes,
还是被视作在关键时刻退缩的懦夫
or as cowards who chickened out when it really came down to it?
士兵们
Soldiers,
我们要竭尽全力向他们发动进攻
we're going to strike now with all our rigour and might.
拉蒂尔属于德国人
Latierre belongs in German hands.
我们要在11点前占领平原
We will seize the plains before 11 a.m.
让这场战争
and end this war
以胜利告终
with a victory!
冲啊
上帝会与我们同在
Onwards with God who will be with us,
就像他与我们的父辈同在一样
as He was with our fathers.
我不会回去战斗的 我不干
I'm not going back into battle. Not me!
闭嘴
Shut up!
瞄准
Take aim!
不要
-No!
开火
-Fire!
全连人员 停下
Company, halt!
取下步枪
Order arms!
装上刺刀
Fix bayonets!
几点了
What time?
还有15分钟
Fifteen minutes to go.
这是勒菲弗的
Belonged to Lefèvre.
那可怜的小子想留到结束时喝的
Poor bastard. He saved it for the end.
他再也不需要了
-He won't need it any more.
谢谢长官
-Thank you, sir.
敬您和勒菲弗
Here's to you and to?Lefèvre.
真好喝
Well, it's good.
噩梦结束了
The nightmare is over.
有敌人进攻
Enemy attack!
-全体就位  -全体就位
-In position! -In position!
开火
Fire!
手榴弹
Grenades!
进攻
Charge!
不要
No, no! Please!
不 不要啊
No! Don't! No!
停火
Cease fire!
11点了
It's eleven o'clock!
停火
Cease fire!
11点了
It's eleven o'clock!
你还好吧 士兵
Are you all right, soldier?
嗯
Yes.
那么请开始收集吧
Well, then… Start collecting, please.
（1914年10月开始敌对行动后不久）
SHORTLY AFTER THE BEGINNING OF THE WAR IN OCTOBER 1914,
（西线就陷入了堑壕战）
THE WESTERN FRONT BECAME BOGGED DOWN IN TRENCH WARFARE.
（直到1918年11月战争结束之时）
AT THE END OF THE WAR IN NOVEMBER 1918,
（前线几乎没有移动）
THE FRONT LINE HAD BARELY MOVED.
（超过300万士兵在这里丧生）
MORE THAN THREE MILLION SOLDIERS DIED HERE,
（通常只是为了挺进几百米而奋战）
OFTEN WHILE FIGHTING TO GAIN ONLY A FEW HUNDRED METRES OF GROUND.
（将近1700万人在一战中丧生）
DURING THE FIRST WORLD WAR, ALMOST 17 MILLION PEOPLE LOST THEIR LIVES.
片名：西线无战事
ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT
字幕翻译：先思瑾